# **AMY WILFORD**

Toronto, ON

linkedin.com/in/amywilford | github.com/AmyWilford | amywilford.github.io/aw-portfolio

#### **SUMMARY:**

With a decade of professional experience spanning Arts & Culture, Education, and Technology sectors, I am a Frontend Developer who brings a multifaceted background to the table. From teacher, program manager and now, developer, my diverse expertise fuels my fresh perspective designing and developing impactful applications and websites. I embrace collaboration with an open mind, infusing creativity into every project while prioritizing efficiency and utility. I am an imaginative problem solver and quick learner with a keen attention to detail who can turn ideas into tangible realities.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS:**

### **Languages, Frameworks & Applications:**

Bootstrap, CSS, Express.js, Git, Handlebars, HTML, JavaScript, JQuery, MySQL, MongoDB, Node.js, PHP, React.js, React Native, REST API, SASS, Typescript, Wordpress, XML

#### **PROJECTS:**

## BAY OF QUINTE GREEN PARTY OF ONTARIO | https://bayofquintegpo.ca/

- Summary: A custom wordpress theme designed for local Green Party of Ontario riding.
- Role: Developer and Designer
- CSS | HTML | JavaScript | PHP | Wordpress

## GIRL MEET MONEY DIAGNOSTIC QUIZ | https://girlmeetmoney.com/pages/gmm-diagnostic-quiz

- Summary: A custom built widget embedded into the GMM shopify site. This is a multiple choice quiz that determines a users 'money blueprint' and directs user-traffic to client online courses
- Role: Developer and Designer
- HTML | CSS | JavaScript | Shopify | Github Pages (to host widget source code)

# **RATE THE GORDS** | ratethegords.ca

- Summary: Canada has a lot of iconic Gords and this is the site where you can rate them. Rate the Gords is a fully-responsive MERN Stack application
- Role: Developer and Designer
- React.js|MongoDB|Mongoose|Node|Express|CSS|JavaScript|JSX|Bootstrap

# **CUE CARDS** | <u>https://tinyurl.com/2p8bd55p</u>

- Summary: An online study tool that allows you to make your own cue cards and quiz you on your understanding of the content. A fully-responsive MERN stack application
- Role: Developer and Designer
- React.js|MongoDB|Mongoose|Node|Express|CSS |JavaScript|JSX|Bootstrap

#### **EXPERIENCE:**

#### WEB DEVELOPER | ENTREMISSION (contract), Montréal, QC (remote) | 2023 - current

- Developed highly customised WordPress themes and plugins using ACFPro and SearchWP to create tailored websites with integrated databases and advanced search engines.
- Collaborated with team senior developer to integrate backend data and optimise website function for enhanced user experience.
- Applied a combination of Javascript, PHP, HTML, and REST API to build and integrate custom
  widgets and site elements into client websites to optimise user engagement and present
  dynamic content based on client needs and designer specs.
- Demonstrated strong problem-solving and research skills, and proposed solutions to address technical issues and persistent bugs

# WEB DEVELOPER | INDEPENDENT CONTRACTOR, Toronto ON | 2021 - current

- Leveraged expertise in HTML, CSS/SASS, JavaScript, and PHP to design, develop, and maintain fully customised and responsive websites.
- Collaborated with clients to translate requirements into designs, while effectively communicating project timelines and milestones throughout the development process.
- Managed end-to-end deployment processes, including domain configuration, SSL certificates, and client setup, guaranteeing seamless and successful site deployments.

# **FUNDRAISING & DEVELOPMENT COORDINATOR | LUMINATO FESTIVAL,** *Toronto ON |* 2021-2022

- Developed policies and procedures to ensure data integrity across departments and oversaw accurate records management in CRM system (Raiser's Edge)
- Researched and streamlined database management systems and created a detailed CRM user manual for organization-wide use
- Consistently met goals to grow, analyse, and report on the organisation's donor pipeline.

## TEACHER TRAINING COORDINATOR & FACULTY MEMBER | SAANA YOGA, Toronto ON | 2019-2021

- Designed, built, and coordinated three unique yoga teacher training programs, and engineered the shift to online learning during COVID
- Directed a teaching faculty of 10+ to compile course curriculums & training schedules.
- Refined communication skills as a faculty member and training cohort mentor

# **DEVELOPMENT & ENGAGEMENT SPECIALIST | SWIM DRINK FISH**, Toronto ON | 2014-2018

 Conceived, created, and executed community & online engagement campaigns that achieved fundraising targets. Monitored budgets, delivered compelling campaign assets, and collaborated on design communication strategies.

# **EDUCATION:**

- 2022 | Full Stack Web Development Certificate, University of Toronto SCS Toronto ON
- 2021 | JavaScript and React.js Certificate, Seneca College Toronto ON
- 2012 | Postgraduate Diploma Not-for-Profit Management, Western University -London ON
- 2011 | Bachelor of Music, Performance (BMus), Western University London ON